Guide to the Veranus A. Moore Papers, 1836-1958
Moore, Veranus A. papers, 1836-1958
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Veranus A. Moore papers, 1836-1958
24-01-119
Veranus A.(Veranus Alva) Moore 1859-1931.
33 cubic ft.
Correspondence, ephemera, clippings, diaries, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, biographical information, photographs, clippings, and other material pertaining to Moore's life and his career as a bacteriologist, veterinary pathologist, professor and Dean of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Veranus Alva Moore was born in Houndsfield (Hounsfield), NY, on April 13, 1859. He was raised in Oswego County, New York. When he was 14 years old, he stepped on a nail which caused an infection that kept him on crutches for the next ten years. During those years, Veranus struggled to finish his education while helping his mother support the family and raise his three younger brothers.
In 1883 he entered Cornell University. His work was so impressive that Dr. Simon Henry Gage recommended him for a position with the U.S. Department of Agriculture's Bureau of Animal Industry before he had completed his degree. He left for Washington in January 1887, wrote his undergraduate thesis in his spare time, and returned in June to graduate with his class. The following fall he entered Columbian (now George Washington) University. He took classes in the evenings and studied during weekends and vacations and received his M.D. in 1890.
Moore's career centered around the study and control of infectious diseases afflicting food animals. He worked for the Bureau of Animal Industry until 1896, then returned to Cornell to become one of the original six professors of the newly founded New York State Veterinary College. He taught Comparative Pathology and Bacteriology as well as meat inspection. In 1908 he became the second dean of the college, succeeding James Law. He served in that post until 1929, and died only two years later on February 11, 1931.
More information about Moore can be found in the "Biography" series in this collection as well as in American National Biography
CHRONOLOGY
1859 Born on April 13 in Houndsfield (Hounsfield), New York
1887 B.S., Cornell University
1887 Hired by the Bureau of Animal Industry
1890 M.D., Columbian (George Washington) University
1892 Married Mary L. Slawson on July 12
1893 Erwin Veranus Moore born on December 24
1896 Mary Eastman Moore (Shackleton) born on November 5
1896 Joined the faculty of the New York State Veterinary College
1901 Norman Slawson Moore born on April 17
1908 Became the second dean of the New York State Veterinary College
1911 V.M D.(Honorary), University of Pennsylvania
1919 Doctor of Science (Honorary), Syracuse University
1929 Retired from the New York State Veterinary College
1929 Became the director of Ithaca Memorial Hospital
1931 Died on February 11 at the age of 71 following intestinal surgery at Ithaca Memorial Hospital
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, subject files, photographs, clippings, and other material pertaining to Moore's life and his career in veterinary medicine and public health.
The collection includes biographical information and genealogical information in the form of Moore family correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings, financial ledgers, a scrapbook, and correspondence with friends such as Martin H. Goodkind, Warren D. More, and Ora P. Rider.
There is also an abundance of information about Cornell University and the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine, ranging from Moore's undergraduate years through his more than twenty years as Dean.
Much of the correspondence, subject files and ephemera in the collection comes from Moore's involvement in professional organizations such as the American Public Health Association, American Veterinary Medical Association, New York State Veterinary Medical Society, Society of American Bacteriologists, Tompkins County Medical Society, United States Livestock Sanitary Association, and World's Dairy Congress Association. There is also an abundance of material relating to his membership in a number of fraternal and civic organizations, such as the Cosmos Club, the Masons, Phi Kappa Phi, Phi Sigma Kappa, the Ithaca City Hospital and the Ithaca Board of Education.
There are also a number of files documenting Moore's consulting work with companies and institutions such as the Anaconda Copper Mining Company, Borden, Briarcliff Farms, and the Milbank Memorial Fund. There is also an abundance of material regarding Moore's work on the formation of the United States Army Veterinary Corps.
The subject files in this collection cover a broad range of topics. Of particular note are the materials on bacteriology, brucellosis, the study and teaching of veterinary medicine, microbiology, meat inspection, milk hygiene, public health (especially in New York State), sexual hygiene instruction, vivisection, human tuberculosis, and bovine tuberculosis
Correspondence with veterinary and public health specialists comprises the bulk of the Moore collection. Significant correspondents include Bernhard Bang, Jean Broadhurst, Samuel H. Burnett, George Washington Carver, Cooper Curtice, W. W. Dimock, R. R. Dykstra. P.A. Fish, C.P. Fitch, Mark Francis, Langdon Frothingham, H.C. Gardiner, Ward Giltner, W.G. Hollingsworth, Grant Sherman Hopkins, William Henry Kelly, Fred L. Kilbourne, James Law, Alexandre Liautard, Winfred B. Mack, Charles Edward Marshall, C.J. Marshall, Duncan McEachran, F.H. McNair, L.A. Merillat, H.J. Milks, Frank H. Miller, J.E. Peabody, H.D. Pease, Leonard Pearson, E.M. Pickens, S.C. Prescott, M.P. Ravenel, M.H. Reynolds, J.G. Rutherford, Daniel Salmon, Theobald Smith, C.H. Stange, D.H. Udall, A.R. Ward, Cassius Way, David Stuart White, Horace White, W.L. Williams, and John G. Wills.
The ephemera in the collection includes, buttons, pins, ribbons, maps, posters, and visiting cards (calling cards).
For a complete listing of all subjects and correspondents, please see the container list.
The earliest material, which dates from the 1830s is in the Family Papers Series. The most recent material dates from the 1950s and is included in the "Posthumous Memorials" folder in the Biography series and in the "Vivisection" Subject Files. It is unclear how the most recent vivisection material (Box 29, Folder 22) became part of the collection. Moore died in 1931, yet the material dates up to 1958. It is possible that the material was added by Dr. Norman Moore, his son, or that material from other collections was mixed with the Moore material in the years between original transfer and processing.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Moore, Veranus A. (Veranus Alva), 1859-1931.; Bang, Bernhard Lauritz Frederik, 1848-1932.; Broadhurst, Jean.; Burnett, Samuel H.; Carver, George Washington.; Curtice, Cooper.; Dimock, W. W. (William Wallace), 1880-; Dykstra, R. R. (Ralph Ralph), 1879-; Fish, Pierre Augustine, 1865-1931.; Fitch, C. P.; Francis, M., 1863-1936.; Frothingham, Langdon.; Gardiner, H. C.; Giltner, Ward, 1882-; Goodkind, Martin H.; Hollingsworth, W.G.; Hopkins, Grant Sherman, 1865-; Kelly, William Henry.; Kilbourne, Fred L.; Law, James, 1838-1921.; Liautard, Alexandre François Augustin, 1835-1918.; Mack, Winfred B.; Marshall, Charles Edward, 1866-1927.; Marshall, C.J.; McEachran, D. 1841-1924 (Duncan); McNair, F.H.; Merillat, Louis A. 1868- (Louis Adolph); Milks, Howard Jay, 1879-; Miller, Frank H.; Moore family.; More, Warren D.; Peabody, J.E.; Pease, H.D., 1870-; Pearson, Leonard, 1868-; Pickens, E.M.; Prescott, Samuel Cate, 1872-; Ravenel, Mazyck Porcher; Reynolds, Myron Herbert, 1865-; Rider, Ora P.; Rutherford, John Gunion, 1857-; Salmon, D E., 1850-1914.; Smith, Theobald, 1859-1934.; Stange, Charles Henry, 1880-1936.; Udall, Denny Hammond, 1874-; Ward, Archibald Robinson, 1875-; Way, Cassius.; White, David Stuart, 1869-; White, Horace, 1865-1943.; Williams, Walter Long, 1856-1945.; Wills, John G.; American Public Health Association.; American Veterinary Medical Association.; Anaconda Copper Mining Company.; Borden Company.; Briarcliff Farms (Briarcliff Manor, N.Y.); Cosmos Club (Washington, D.C.); Freemasons.; Ithaca City Hospital.; Ithaca (N.Y.). Board of Education.; MacMillan & Co.; Milbank Memorial Fund.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.; New York State Veterinary Medical Society.; Phi Kappa Phi.; Phi Sigma Kappa.; Society of American Bacteriologists.; Tompkins County Medical Society.; United States Army. Veterinary Corps.; United States Livestock Sanitary Association.; World's Dairy Congress Association.
Subjects:
Bacteriology.; Brucellosis.; Hygiene, Sexual.; Meat inspection.; Microbiology.; Milk hygiene.; Public Health--New York (State); Tuberculosis.; Tuberculosis in cattle.; Veterinary medicine--Study and teaching.; Vivisection.
Form and Genre Terms:
Buttons (information artifacts).; Journals (accounts).; Maps.; Photographs.; Posters.; Scrapbooks.; Visiting cards.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
RMC Collection #13-06-2082. Norman S. Moore oral history, 1985.
Olin F129. I8.M66 1996+. Published transcript of a 1994 interview with Norman Moore.
RMC Collection #51-01-1368. Norman Moore papers, 1919-1994.
RMC Collection #37-05-3133. Shackleton family collection, 1914-1921.
RMC Collection #14-22-46. Ernest George Merritt papers, 1887-1950.
RMC Collection #20-01-287. Dept. of Forestry records, 1912-1915.
RMC Collection #21-24-97. Carl E. Ladd Director of Extension papers, 1924-1930.
RMC Collection #36-01-630. Cornell University Office of the Registrar Records.
RMC Collection #2541. New York State Veterinary Medical Society Records.
RMC Collection #2552. Alice Catherine Evans Papers.
RMC Collection #2607. Harry George Stutz Papers.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
This collection is an amalgamation of several separate collections of different origin. Over a period of approximately sixty years, the official records of the Dean's Office of the College of Veterinary Medicine during Moore's tenure as well as that of James Law were mixed with the personal papers of Veranus Moore and his son Norman Moore. At some point in the 1950s the files were rehoused and reorganized in one chronological run. In 2002-2003 the collection was again reprocessed to provide better access to significant material. There is still a series of chronological "miscellaneous" files, but correspondence from particularly noteworthy individuals and institutions as well as frequent correspondents have been separated. Other material, such as biographical information, subject files and ephemera, have been separated into their own series. Thus the structure of the collection is purely artificial and no conclusions should be drawn about Moore's priorities or modus operandi from the folder arrangement.
Some Dean's Office records from Moore's tenure may have been lost when the College moved from James Law Hall to Schurman Hall in 1959. This is evidenced by an 1899 letter from Cooper Curtice to Moore found at the Law Hall "wrecking site" in 1959 by Mrs. Theodore S Lisberger. The letter is now located in the Cooper Curtice folder in Series III. Correspondence.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biography
Boxes 1-2, 26, 31, 35-37
The Biography Series includes general information about Moore's life and career. There are narratives written by himself and others, newspaper clippings, obituaries and memorials. There is information about his childhood, finances, daily schedules, retirement and death. Included in the material about his death are the cards which accompanied flowers sent by friends and family. The cards are annotated on the reverse (presumably by his wife) with descriptions of the arrangements. There is also a series of journals and ledgers kept by Moore throughout his life. They track, alternately and in combination, his finances, appointments, acquaintances and research projects. There is more biographical material in Series VII. Family Papers, in a scrapbook created by Antoinette Moore. The scrapbook includes graduation programs and wedding invitations.
Series II. Education
Boxes 1, 26, 31, 32
The Education Series includes material relating to Moore's academic training from grade school through college. A number of note books comprise the bulk of the series. Most date from Moore's undergraduate years at Cornell. There is also a box (number 32) of index cards Moore compiled on various subjects during his education at Cornell. There is another box (number 33) of cards Moore created to keep track of articles, books and periodicals on various subjects. That box is listed under Series V. Subject Files.
Series III. Correspondence
Boxes 3-18, 26, 27, 36, 37
This series comprises the bulk of the Veranus Moore papers. The material is organized alphabetically by correspondent, followed by a chronological run of "miscellaneous" correspondence. The correspondence labeled "miscellaneous" is neither unimportant nor irrelevant. The letters are simply not from a frequent correspondent or one easily identifiable as a key figure in Moore's personal or professional life. Much of the correspondence is from local farmers and veterinarians asking for advice or tuberculin, but there are also letters regarding developments in the the medical and veterinary professions, political and civic issues, and Moore's personal affairs. There are many letters from Cornell alumni, including a number of letters from alumni serving overseas during World War I.
Some of the correspondence addressed to the Veterinary College was answered by Moore's assistants, such as Cassius Way, Walter J. Taylor, Winfred B. Mack, Samuel H. Burnett and E.M. Pickens. There is also an abundance of correspondence addressed to and answered by William A. Hagan.
Series IV. Writings
Boxes 18-20, 27, 36
The Writings series includes drafts of and notes for Moore's published works. The series also includes notes and full texts of speeches. Although some newspaper and magazine articles have been kept in this series, most published versions of his work have been removed. His books are available from the Cornell University Libraries. Reprints of his articles are available in the Historical Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet collection.
Series V. Subject Files
Boxes 20-22, 27-29, 33, 34, 36, 37
The Subject Files series consists of a combination of files created by Veranus Moore and files created by the archivist. The files contain publications on a wide variety of topics, including many specific diseases, vivisection, public health issues, legislation relating to the veterinary profession, sex education and venereal disease, as well as veterinary and medical education. There are files in this series (as well as in the Correspondence series) about the formation of the United States Army Veterinary Corps. There are also files from cases Moore consulted on, such as the Anaconda Copper Mining Company Case and the tuberculosis surveys of Cattaraugus County (sponsored by the Milbank Memorial Fund). There are also several files of miscellaneous research and reading notes, including a box (number 33) of index cards Moore compiled early in his career. Another box of index cards (number 32) was compiled during his education at Cornell. That box is listed under Series II. Education.
Series VI. Ephemera
Boxes 22-25, 29, 31, 32, 36-38
The Ephemera series includes various and sundry items collected by Moore throughout his life time, such as conference and professional association programs; conference pins, buttons, and ribbons; posters and maps; advertisements; calling cards; family Bibles; and Masonic handbooks.
Series VII. Family Papers
Boxes 25, 30, 35, 44
The Family Papers series consists of materials gathered and created by the Moore, Slawson, and Shackleton families. The bulk of the series consists of correspondence, but there are also diaries, financial records, note books and a scrapbook created by Antoinette Moore, mother of Veranus.
Series VIII. Photographs
Boxes 39- 43
The Photographs series consists of images of Veranus Moore, his family, and friends, as well as images of the New York State Veterinary College, its faculty, staff, and students. There are also images from his research and consultation work. There are several images of significant veterinarians and physicians, as well as several noted members of the Cornell faculty and staff. Examples include Bernard Bang, Cooper Curtice, Jacob Gould Schurman, Duncan McEachran, Samuel Prescott, and others.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biography
  - Narrative, V.A. Moore, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Narrative, Pierre A. Fish, ca. 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Narrative, Simon Henry Gage, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Narrative, s.n., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Narrative, s.n., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1896-1929, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Original newspaper clippings and articles for exhibits (copies available in Box 1 folder 6 and in Series IV. Writings), 1897-1929 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Awards, 1905, 1911, 1922, 1928 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Retirement [ See also Correspondence-New York State Veterinary Medical Society.], 1929 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Death
    - Get Well Letters, Jan-Feb 1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Obituaries, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Obituaries (oversized originals), 1931 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Simon H. Gage File, 1927, 1929, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Sympathy Notes, A-G, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Sympathy Notes, H-M, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Sympathy Notes, N-Z, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Sympathy Notes, No Last Name, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Sympathy Notes, Organizations, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Flower Arrangement cards, 1931 (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous, 1913-1931 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Posthumous Memorials, 1939-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Automobiles, 1912-1928 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Finances
    - General, 1892-1930, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Receipts, 1881-1905, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Receipts, 1881-1905, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Real Estate, 1896, 1911, 1915 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Real Estate - Barn Blue Print, 1915 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Grade School Teaching, 1880-1882 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1895-1931 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Journals and Ledgers
    - Volume 1 - Accounts, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Volume 2 - Accounts, 1887-1888 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Volume 3 - Accounts, 1887-1889 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Volume 4 - Accounts, 1889-1890 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Volume 5 - Accounts, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Volume 6 - Accounts, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Volume 7 - Accounts, 1893-1896 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Volume 8 - Accounts, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Volume 9 - Accounts, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Volume 10 - Accounts, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Volume 11 - Accounts, 1900-1918 (Box 35)
    - Volume 12 - Accounts, 1919-1921 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Volume 13 - Accounts, 1922-1926 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Volume 14 - Accounts, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Volume 15 - Accounts, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Volume 16 - Accounts, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Volume 17 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, ca. 1903 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Volume 18 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, ca. 1904 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Volume 19 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Volume 20 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1907-1908 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Volume 21 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Volume 22 - Expenses and Addresses, ca. 1908 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Volume 23 - Dates, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Volume 24 - Dates and Addresses, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Volume 25 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Volume 26 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Volume 27 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Volume 28 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Volume 29 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Volume 30 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Volume 31 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Volume 32 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Volume 33 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Volume 34 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Volume 35 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Volume 36 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Volume 37 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Volume 38 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Volume 39 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Volume 40 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Volume 41 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Volume 42 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Volume 43 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Volume 44 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Volume 45 - Dates, Addresses & Expenses, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Volume 46 - Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Volume 47 - Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Volume 48 - Birthday Book, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Volume 49 - Addresses, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Volume 50 - Addresses, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Volume 51 - Bank Book, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Volume 52 - Diary, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Volume 53 - Diary, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Volume 54 - Diary, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Volume 55 - Diary, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Volume 56 - BAI Field Diary, ca. 1890-1896 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Volume 57 - European Travel Journal, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Volume 58 - Miscellaneous Notes, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Volume 59 - Miscellaneous Notes, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Volume 60 - Miscellaneous Accounts, 1898-1900 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series II. Education
  - Childhood Writings, ca. 1865-1883 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Sketches, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - West Monroe Select School, 1875-1876, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Mexico Academy, 1879-1929, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cornell University, 1883-1887 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Cornell University-Class of 1887 [ See also Series III. Correspondence-Goodkind, Martin H. and Correspondence-Himes, Albert J., 1902-1931, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Columbia University - cards received on graduation [ See also Series VI. Ephemera-George Washington University, 1890 (Box 31)
  - Notebooks
    - "Animal Classification", 1884 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Botany, ca. 1884 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Botany, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Chemistry, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "Classification of Plants", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - "Drawings of Brain and Notes on Anatomy" (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - English Literature, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Entomology, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - "Ferns", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - "Fungi", 1885 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Fungi, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - German, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Medicinal Plants of Cayuga Lake, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Medicinal Plants, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - "Medicinal Plants of E.U.S. and Cayuga Lake Flora" (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "Modern History" with Professor Adams, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "Mosses", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - "Organic Chemistry", 1885 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - "The Primary List of Plants Used in Medicine Found in the U.S." (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Qualitative Analysis, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Rhetoric, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Rhetoric, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Veterinary Science, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - "Woody Plants", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 47)